Miss Wan! Miss Wan!
菀青老师 菀青老师
Brother Sikong, he...
司空哥哥他
What happened to him?
他又怎么了呀
Miss Wan! Miss Wan!
菀青老师 菀青老师
Look!
你看
Wan Qing,
菀青
I heard that Kongming lanterns will make wishes come true easily.
听说孔明灯许愿特别灵
Let's make a wish together!
我们一起许个愿吧
Make a wish! Make a wish!
许愿 许愿
From now on,
从此以后
I'll hold your hand
执子之手
and grow old together with you.
与子偕老
From now on,
从此以后
we'll help each other in difficult times.
相濡以沫
We're not alone anymore.
不再孤单
Make a wish! Make a wish! Make a wish!
许愿 许愿 许愿
Wan Qing,
菀青
I thought that girls love romance.
女子不都喜欢浪漫吗
You...
你这
I hope the glacial poison of Nangong
希望南宫的寒毒
can be cured soon.
能早日找到解药痊愈
It's nice to accompany Qingqing like this.
能这样陪在卿卿身边也很好
I hope that
希望
I can be with her forever.
可以一直陪着她
Qingqing,
卿儿
let's go somewhere else.
走 我们到别处看看
Take it easy.
没关系
Let's do it again.
再来
Come on.
你再来
You got it!
你中了
Why?
为什么
Why do you only care about Lu Qingqing?
你的眼里只有路卿卿
Qingqing,
卿儿
this looks beautiful.
这个好看
Excuse me,
老板
I'll take both of them.
这俩我都要了
Sure.
好
Your Highness.
太子殿下
Pay respect to you.
太子金安
Is the Lantern Festival interesting?
上元节好玩吗
Yes!
好玩
The lanterns party is flourishing!
花灯会真热闹
It's so interesting.
特别好玩
Yes,
是啊
the Lantern Festival is busy.
上元节挺热闹的
This is my first time to join in it.
我还是第一次来
[herbal medicine shop]
大家喜欢就好
Pay attention to your safety.
注意安全
OK, then we won't bother you.
那我们就不打扰了
We're gonna leave.
就不打扰了
Qingqing?
卿儿
Let me go.
放开我
No.
不放
Let me go. I'll hurt you.
放开我 我会伤害你的
Qingqing.
卿卿
Qingqing, listen to me.
卿卿你听我说
I went through all the ancient books
我翻了所有的古籍
but failed to find a method to cure your glacial poison.
没有找到能够解寒毒的办法
The only thing I can do
我现在唯一能做的
is to stay away from you.
就是离你远一点
That's how I keep you safe.
这样才能保证你的安全
Qingqing!
卿儿
I finally found you.
我可算找到你了
Brother, you are also here.
王兄也在
Thank you for taking care of Qingqing these days.
多谢你这几天帮我照顾卿卿
You are welcome.
不用客气
Taking care of Qingqing makes me happy,
照顾卿儿本是铭炀满心欢喜
so I'm willing to do it.
且心甘情愿之事
Since you're not feeling well,
王兄既然身体不适
why don't you have a good rest at home?
为何不在府中好好休息
Qingqing,
卿儿
I am glad that you are fine.
你没事就好
Go.
走
Let me go.
都放开我
Don't follow me, both of you.
谁都别跟着我
Be careful!
小心
Qingqing!
卿儿
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Are you in pain again?
又疼了吗
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
对不起 都怪我
Qingqing!
卿儿
Nangong...
南宫他
Brother.
王兄
Lingyu,
凌宇
send my brother back home.
送王兄回去
Yes.
是
Qingqing,
卿儿
why can you be cared for by so many people?
为何你能收获这么多的关怀
My lady,
小姐
didn't you go to blessing in
您不是和太子
the Latern Festival with Crown Prince?
去上元节祈福了吗
Why are you back so early?
怎么这么早就回来了
There was an accident.
出了点意外
Accident?
意外
Don't worry.
别担心
It was just that I almost fell into water.
就是差点落水而已
I'm okay.
我没事
But he...
倒是他
I made him get hurt again.
我又害他受伤了
Is Lord Jin also there?
晋王也在
He loves you so deeply, my lady.
他对小姐真是一片痴心
Knowing it would hurt to approach you,
明明知道接近您会受伤
he keeps coming to see you.
还这么锲而不舍
He must have remembered that I can't swim.
他肯定是记得我不会水
He came to save me
怕我落水
from drowning.
所以才来救我的吧
My lady,
小姐
don't blame yourself too much.
您别太自责了
I wonder how well he is now.
也不知道他现在身体怎么样
Mingyang.
铭炀
Brother!
王兄
Where is Qingqing?
卿卿呢
Take it easy, my brother.
王兄放心吧
I've already sent her back home.
我已经派人送她回府了
You'd better not see
你以后还是
Qingqing again anymore.
不要和卿卿再见面了
I've already controlled the poison in my body.
我已经控制住体内的寒毒了
Have you?
控制住了
Then why did you faint today?
那为何今日还会晕厥
Because...
因为
I need to seal my magic power to control the glacial poison.
控制寒毒需要封印灵力
I used my magic power in an emergency today.
今天情急之下我使用了灵力
I forgot the doctor's orders.
我忘记了大夫的嘱咐
Without magic power?
没有灵力
Then how could you protect yourself?
那你日后该如何自保啊
I stay in No Magic Valley all year long,
我常年待在废灵谷
o it doesn't matter
其实有没有灵力
even if I have no magic power.
也没什么大碍
For Qingqing,
为了卿儿
he even gives up his magic power.
他竟然连灵力都不要了
Brother,
王兄
you have given up so many things for Qingqing,
你为了卿儿放弃了这么多
so I respect you.
我很佩服
But it was also Qingqing that
但也是卿儿让我第一次
first gave me the urge to go for it.
有了想去争取的冲动
So I won't give up, either.
所以我也不会放弃的
Mingyang,
铭炀
I know you like Qingqing very much.
我知道你对卿卿的心意
But my affection for Qingqing
只是你有情意
is the same as yours.
我又何尝不是呢
Qingqing is
卿卿对于我来说
unique to me.
是独一无二的
So, this time
所以这一次
I'd never give up.
我绝对不会放弃
Then let's see who she will choose.
那便看卿儿如何选择吧
My lady,
小姐
drink some porridge.
您喝点粥吧
you are in a bad mood recently
近日您心情不佳
and refuse to eat dinner.
这晚饭也不吃
You need to take care of yourself.
您要注意身体啊
Tell me.
你说太子
Will Crown Prince and Lord Jin turn against each other because of her?
会因为她跟晋王反目吗
Master always serves Crown Prince faithfully.
老爷一向忠心辅佐太子
He doesn't like Lord Jin at all.
又不喜晋王
But Lady Qingqing always gets close to Lord Jin.
那二小姐偏偏与晋王走得最近
If Crown Prince finds out
太子殿下如果哪天发现了
the true features of Lady Qingqing,
二小姐的真面目
he would definitely know that
他一定会知道真心对他好的
you are the one who treats him sincerely.
还是小姐您
Enough.
行了
Don't go back and forth.
你别在这儿晃来晃去了
Look at yourself.
你说你现在
You're just like headless chicken
跟那个废灵谷的无头苍蝇
in No Magic Valley.
有什么区别
I just wanted to explain to her that
我是想跟她解释清楚
I have sealed the glacial poison in my body.
寒毒已解的事情
But I never thought I would pass out in front of her.
谁想到我在她面前晕倒了
Now she's even less likely to see me.
现在她更不可能见我了
Who do you think is to blame for this?
那你说这个事能怪谁
You've been told to take care of your body.
让你爱惜身体你不
Doctor Wu has told you too many times
吾大夫跟你说了多少次了
not to use your magic power.
让你别用灵力
What did you do?
你呢
You Broke the rules as soon as you get back.
刚回来就破戒
She almost fell into the water.
她当时差点就掉水里了
I had no other choice. It was urgent.
情势所迫 我没办法嘛
No other choice?
没办法
Qingqing has magic power now.
卿卿现在有灵力了
She would react before she hits water.
她还没落水自然会反应过来
She can save herself.
会自己上来
She's got more magic power than you do.
她现在灵力比你还强
You...
你
I never thought I'd
想不到终有一天
end up like you in love.
落得跟你一样情场失意
Don't compare me to you about love issues!
你可别什么事都带上我啊
Wan Qing has been so nice to me lately.
菀青最近对我可好了
She is like a different person.
跟变了个人一样
Why?
为什么呀
I don't know.
我也不知道
Maybe
可能
she had been subdued by my personal charisma.
是终于被我的魅力折服了吧
Alright.
行了
You can't see her,
你想见的人见不到
but I can.
我能见啊
Maybe I can ask her out someday
我要不哪天帮你把卿卿约出来
and put in a good word for you.
帮你说点好话
Today is an appropriate day.
择日不如撞日
Right now.
就现在
Right, now.
立刻 马上
Come here. Here.
来 来 来
Come on.
来
Look,
这样
you write a letter to Qingqing
你帮我写一封信给卿卿
and invite her to my home.
你就说把她约到我府上
I'll cook by myself.
我亲自下厨
She'd be happy!
她应该会很开心吧
No. No. No.
不对 不对 不对
If I ask her to come to my home,
如果约到我府上
it's certain that she won't come.
她肯定不会来
So we'd better invite her to the Yuejiao teahouse
所以我们约到月佼茶楼
and I'll cook for her at home.
我还是亲自下厨
After finishing, I'll send the dishes to the teahouse.
然后我做完之后把菜送过去
Nangong,
南宫
you are screwed!
你完了呀
You've fallen into her hands!
你这是完全沦陷了
Look at your attitude
你现在谈到卿卿
when talking about Lu Qingqing.
你看把你急的
I'm the host,
我是一府的主人
so I should take good care of my guest.
我得把这客人照顾好了对吧
OK. OK.
行 行 行
I can help you,
我可以帮你忙
but you should promise not
但是你
to use your magic power.
绝对不用灵力
Your Highness,
殿下
I have prepared well.
属下已经打点好
The guards who patrol the Library Pavilion
今晚巡视藏书阁的人
tonight have been scattered.
都被支开了
Great.
太好了
Lingyu,
凌宇
prepare a carriage for me.
备马车
I will take Qingqing to the Library Pavilion again.
我要带卿儿再去一次藏书阁
And this time,
这次
she can check the ancient books carefully.
她可以好好查查里面的古籍了
Pay respect to you, Lady Qingqing.
见过二小姐
Lingyu?
凌宇
What's the matter?
有什么事吗
Crown Prince invites you to enter the palace
太子殿下请您再到宫中去
and you can read the collection intently.
您可以安心地查阅藏书
Really?
真的吗
That's great!
太好了
Lady Qingqing, please prepare
那二小姐请您收拾一下
and wait for Crown Price to take you
待会儿太子呢
to the palace for the feast.
接您到宫中赴宴
Baihe,
百合
help me with my makeup, quickly!
快帮我梳妆
I'll go to a feast tonight.
今晚我要去赴宴
But...what about Lord Sikong?
可是司空大人那边怎么办
It doesn't matter.
没事
You can go and tell him that
你帮我去跟他说
I'll invite him some other day.
说我改日再约他
Xiaowu,
小武
do you think these dishes are enough?
你说做这些菜够吗
Will she like them?
她会喜欢吗
That's enough, Your Highness.
够了 王爷
If you keep cooking,
您再这么做下去
the dishes will be enough
咱们整个府上下
for the whole family.
今晚的饭都够了
You know what?
跟你说啊
As long as she likes them.
只要她喜欢就好
She lost weight the last time I saw her.
上次我见她都瘦了
Lost weight?
瘦了
Why didn't I feel that?
小的怎么没觉得她瘦
Pretty good.
还不错
Your Grace,
大人
as you expected,
如您所料
Lady Qingqing has stopped seeing Lord Jin recently.
二小姐最近不再与晋王见面
Great.
很好
But Crown prince has met
倒是太子殿下
Lady Qingqing many times recently.
最近频频与二小姐见面
He also invited Lady Qingqing to enter the palace
今晚太子殿下
and have dinner together tonight.
还邀二小姐进宫用膳
Estrange her from Lord Jin
疏远晋王
and let her accept the Crown Prince's kindness.
太子又趁此机会对卿卿用心
We may hear
看来不日
good news from them soon.
就能得到二人的好消息了
If so,
如此
you can get the magic power stone soon.
大人便能很快得到灵力石了
Your Grace,
大人
I just saw the carriage of Crown Prince
适才属下看到太子殿下的马车
came to the gate of our mansion.
到了府门口
I think it's picking up Lord Qingqing.
应该是来接二小姐的
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
怎么不早说呢
Quickly! Quickly!
快 快 快
Qingqing...
卿卿
Pay respects to you, Your Highness.
太子金安
Lord Lu.
路大人
You have invited my daughter Qingqing frequently recently
太子最近接连邀约小女卿卿
with great care.
十分用心
I heard that you are getting along very well.
微臣听说太子与小女相处甚欢
I'm delighted to hear that.
甚是欣慰
If you need any
如果太子有什么
help from me,
需要微臣帮忙的
just let me know.
尽管开口
I'll support you as much as I can.
微臣定可助太子一臂之力
Thank you for your kindness.
路大人有心了
It's just that I can't
只是本王对路大人的手段
approve of your methods.
万不能苟同
A few days ago,
前两日
I heard that you were so stunned
我听说路大人
by what Qingqing
对卿卿的所作所为
had done.
万分惊骇
But I didn't expect that
不承想
you could even
路大人连自己的亲生女儿
hurt your own daughter.
都不放过
I wonder what you're talking about.
微臣不知殿下所说何事
I think there's been some misunderstanding between us.
这其中是否有什么误会啊
You are a prudent
路大人行事严谨
and resourceful person,
耳聪目明
so you must understand what I'm talking about.
您知道我在说什么
Please don't interfere in
本王与卿卿的事
the affair between Qingqing and me.
请路大人以后不要再插手
Yes, Your Highness.
是 太子
Your Grace.
大人
You can leave.
下去吧
Crown prince became more and more angry with me.
太子对我愈加不满了
If he does take the throne,
如果真让他登了基
he's gonna kick me out of the way.
一定会一脚把我踢开
After getting the magic stone,
一旦拿到灵力石
I need to clear away this piece of chess.
这颗棋子必不可留
Your Highness,
王爷
you've prepared for Lady Qingqing
您为卿卿小姐
so many dishes,
准备了这么多饭菜
she would be very happy
到时候她来了
if she comes.
一定很高兴
I'm coming.
我来了
Alright, stop.
行了 别看了
She didn't come with me.
人没来
Let's eat.
吃饭
Where is Qingqing?
卿卿她人呢
She can't come here today.
她今天来不了了
What the hell happened?
到底发生什么事
Why couldn't she come?
为什么来不了
She was picked up by Crown Prince.
让太子接走了呗
The dishes taste good.
菜挺好的
Xiaowu, carriage.
小武 备车
Yes, Your Highness.
是 王爷
What?
干吗
Where are you going?
你要干吗去
Qingqing,
卿儿
I think you haven't had
想必你这几日
a good meal for a long time.
都没有好好用膳吧
I haven't
正好
eaten dinner either.
我也还未用膳
Let's have dinner while chatting.
我们边吃边聊
Lord Jin...
晋王殿下
Such a big meal!
这么大一桌酒菜
You two didn't even invite me!
你俩居然不叫我
Your Highness,
殿下
Lord Jin said he wanted to speak with you
晋王殿下说有事找您
and I haven't had a chance to report.
我还没来得及禀报
Brother, you are ill now,
王兄身体不适
so you'd better rest at home
应当在府里休息
rather than hang out randomly.
不该到处乱跑
I have heart disease.
我这个病是心病
Lying down all day is not
天天那么躺着
conducive to my recovery.
也好不了呀
Now that you're here,
晋王殿下来这里
you should have something important to tell Crown Prince.
应该是有事要和太子殿下商量
Then I won't bother anymore.
那我就不打扰了
I'll leave...
卿卿先回去
Stop. Stop.
别 别 别
I have nothing important to say.
我这个闲人能有什么事啊
It's just that the weather tonight is pretty good,
我见今晚风清月圆
so I came to find Mingyang to have a drink
所以就想找铭炀小酌几杯
and have a relax.
消遣消遣
But today,
今日我与卿儿
I want to talk to Qingqing.
约好了有要事要谈
If you want to drink with me,
若王兄想喝酒
I'll prepare good wine and food and
待我改日备上好酒好菜
invite you some other day, okay?
我们再约如何
Qingqing,
卿卿
do you agree with him?
你也是这意思吗
Alright. Why are we standing?
行了 别愣着了
Take a seat.
入席吧
Come on,
来
add one more set of chopsticks here.
给这儿加一副碗筷
Yes.
是
Qingqing, take it easy.
卿儿放心
I'll keep your secret.
我一定帮你守好秘密
Qingqing,
卿儿
come here.
来
come on, have a try.
来 尝尝这个
Eat the shrimp.
吃个虾吧
And a meatball.
再来个丸子
Vegetable is good for your health.
多吃蔬菜身体好
We should have a good appetizer before eating.
吃饭前咱们先开开胃
Qingqing,
卿儿
how is it?
味道如何
Made by the chef in the palace,
宫中大厨做的
of course they are delicious.
自然是差不了
Eat more.
多吃点
Mingyang,
铭炀
the dishes look quite substantial,
你这菜呢看着是挺丰盛
but I don't know whether they also taste well.
但却不知道吃起来是什么味道
This shrimp with green vegetable
这个翡翠虾仁
doesn't look good to eat.
看起来就不太顺滑爽口
I didn't know that
铭炀倒是不知
you boast such a high
王兄对菜品
level of research on dishes.
也有如此高的研究
I have spent a long time in No Magic Valley
在废灵谷待久了
and always eat fresh food.
吃的食材呢都比较新鲜
So my taste
这个口味呢
is hard to adapt to the dishes here.
确实是有点下不来
You can ask Qingqing if you don't believe me,
不信你问卿卿
and she definitely knows my feelings.
她也深有体会
I just came back from No Magic Valley.
我刚从废灵谷回来
You can come to my home if you want to try the flavor,
要是你想吃呢去我府上
and I'll cook it for you.
我下厨
I promise you won't be disappointed.
保证不会让你失望
It would be nice to try the ingredients in Ghost Valley.
废灵谷的食材尝鲜固然是好
But I was born in Qiyuan continent,
但卿卿毕竟是启元大陆的人
so the food here suits me better.
还是这里的食材更适合我
You've got a point there.
卿儿说得在理啊
From my perspective,
在铭炀看来
good food and wonderful times
赏味良辰之际
should be shared
应当和契合的人
with the right person.
在一起品尝才更佳
Sometimes what you want is just the opposite,
有时候勉强心意往往适得其反
one step backward and you may find a better way.
退一步才会山高路远
What do you think, my brother?
王兄觉得如何
Compulsion is a kind of
强人所难
paranoia about hopeless love.
是对无望之爱的一种偏执
I'm not that kind of person.
与我无关
I just want my lover
我只是想令心爱的人
to see the truth
拨云见日
and get together with me again.
然后重修于好
I'm full.
我吃饱了
Try his dessert.
尝尝他这甜食
Now that she is full,
卿儿既已吃饱
there's no need for you to force her.
王兄何必强人所难
Of course I know she is full.
我自然是知她温饱
I don't want to impose it on her, either.
哪有强人所难
But, Mingyang,
倒是你 铭炀
have you ever thought about her?
可曾为她考虑
How do you know I haven't thought of her?
王兄又怎知我不为卿儿考虑
If you really knew her taste,
你如果真懂卿儿
you wouldn't have set the meal according to your own taste.
你不会以你自己的口味设菜
Do you really know what she likes?
你真懂她喜欢什么吗
Do you think that you are
难道王兄觉得
the person who knows her the best?
只有你最懂卿儿吗
Qingqing,
卿卿
who knows you the best?
谁最了解你
You know the answer clearly, right?
你最清楚 是吧
Can you stop?
你们两个闹够了没有
It looks like you guys didn't really want to eat this dinner.
看来二位是没有诚意吃这顿饭
I feel on pins and needles here,
卿卿在这里如坐针毡
so I may as well leave now.
不如早走也好
- Qingqing!
卿儿 卿卿
By the way, I have a proposition.
对了 我有个提议
The weather is fine these days,
现在天高气爽
o maybe we can go for an excursion
很适合去外出郊游
to enjoy the scenery.
一览风景
Mingyang,
铭炀
we haven't gone to hunting ground for a long time.
咱们好久没去猎场了吧
Do you dare to go to the hunting ground
明天敢不敢去猎场
and have a match with me tomorrow?
跟我比试比试
Since you're in such high spirits,
既然王兄兴致如此之高
I'd like to have a match with you.
铭炀愿意奉陪
No.
不行
You're sick now.
你现在身体这样
You can't stand the physical exertion.
受不了体力上的消耗
I'm healthy now.
我身体绝对没问题
Don't forget that
别忘了
hunting is my forte.
狩猎是我的拿手强项
Qingqing, you can go with me tomorrow.
卿卿 明天跟我一起去
I don't know how to hunt.
我不懂狩猎
I'll pass.
我还是不去了吧
It's okay. It's okay.
无妨 无妨
Qingqing,
卿卿
if you're gonna go with us tomorrow,
你明天要是去
I'll choose a good horse for you.
我帮你选一匹好马
That's no need.
不必了
I'll prepare everything for Qingqing.
我会为卿儿准备好一切的
Qingqing hasn't agreed to go with us yet.
卿卿又没答应去不去呢
Of course she would hesitate about your invitation.
你邀请她当然要犹豫一下
What's to hesitate about...
有什么可犹豫的
Qingqing,
卿卿
you'll be my best partner when playing cuju.
蹴鞠的时候咱俩是最佳拍档
We are the best opponents
我们也是相互尊敬
with mutual respect and admiration.
又相互钦佩的最佳对手
Alright. Alright.
行了 行了
I'll go.
我去还不行嘛
Your Grace.
大人
If you have nothing else to say today,
今日若没有其它事
the morning court ends.
便退朝吧
Yes.
是
General Murong.
慕容将军
Your Highness,
太子殿下
I have something important to report.
臣有重要事情上报
I received a letter recently,
近日臣收到一封信
and it said that someone killed General Han.
信中说有人害了韩将军
Someone saw the murder case at the scene
而现场有人亲眼所见
and could testify.
可以作证
Where was this letter from?
此信来自何处
I don't know.
臣也不知
The messenger secretly delivered the letter to my study.
送信的人秘密送到臣的书房
I think General Han died in an unnatural way.
臣觉得韩将军死得蹊跷
Now with this letter,
再加上这封秘信
I request to investigate General Han's death thoroughly.
臣认为应该彻查韩将军之死
OK.
好
I'll hand over this case to you.
此事便交给慕容将军查办
Subject to your will.
臣接旨
Qi Yi,
齐翼
you've worked for me for years.
你为我办事多年
How did you make that mistake?
怎可犯这种错误
Your Grace,
大人
it was a dark night so it was hard to tell people.
当时夜黑人杂
That secret defend plotted against me.
那位暗卫心机颇深
It was my fault.
是属下失误
Please forgive me for my fault.
请大人恕罪
Where is that person?
那人现在在哪儿
He is hiding in Lord Jin Mansion.
那人现在藏匿在晋王府中
Lord Jin Mansion?
晋王府
It seems that Nangong Yixin
看来南宫一昕
had already known about this matter.
已经知道这件事了
He should be killed.
这个人留不得了
Your Grace,
大人
according to the palace guard,
听宫中侍卫说
after Lady Qingqing was taken into the palace,
二小姐被太子带到宫中之后
Lord Jin also went to the palace.
晋王殿下便也去了
Crown Prince and Lord Jin
太子和晋王
made an appointment to go hunting at the hunting ground tomorrow.
相约明日去猎场狩猎
They also invited Lady Qingqing.
也邀请了二小姐同去
Hunting ground...
猎场
He just showed up out of nowhere,
他就这样突然出现
so I didn't even have a chance to ask
我根本就没有机会
Crown Prince for clues about the glacial poison.
向太子殿下问关于寒毒的线索
Lord Jin is a spoony man.
这晋王殿下真是个痴情种
He may have
搞不好
misunderstood your relationship with Crown Prince.
他误会了您与太子殿下的关系
You didn't see that
你是没有看到
they quarreled
他们两个针锋相对
just like two kids fighting over candy.
就跟两个抢糖吃的孩童一样幼稚
My lady.
小姐
What does it mean?
这叫什么
It means they are rivals in love and jealous each other when they meet.
这叫情敌见面分外眼红
Don't move.
别动
You love me so much,
你这么爱我
but why aren't you jealous?
你怎么不眼红
Stop.
别闹了
I made it clear to Crown Prince
我已经跟太子殿下明说过了
that we were just friends.
我们只是朋友
He said he would respect my decision.
他说他会尊重我的决定
But do you really think that
可是你真的觉得
Crown Prince cares about you only as a friend?
太子对您只有朋友之情吗
Although I can't be with Nangong right now,
虽然我现在不能跟南宫在一起
I can make sure the one I like is him.
但是我喜欢的人是他
As for the prince,
对于太子
I was destined not to respond to his love.
我注定没有办法回应他的感情
We can just be friends.
只能做朋友
And also, my sister loves him so much.
而且大姐对他情深义重
I need to keep myself apart from him
我得跟他保持好界限
so that no one would take it the wrong way.
以免被别人误会
Love is a really troublesome business.
情这一事真是让人头疼
By the way,
对了
you didn't go to the Library Pavilion today.
今日没去成藏书阁
Will you go there again tomorrow?
明天还去吗
They are going to the hunting ground tomorrow.
他们明日约了去猎场比试
Hunting ground?
猎场
Will you go with them?
您也去
I'm afraid they'd fight again.
我担心他们两个人再起争执
And if Nangong's health goes wrong again,
而且万一南宫的身体再有状况
I'll be worried.
我不放心
My lady,
小姐
take it easy.
您不要太担心了
His poison wouldn't break out
如今您只要保持距离
as long as you keep the distance with him.
他的寒毒就不会再发作
He has no problem riding and hunting.
骑马打猎自是不在话下
I hope so.
但愿如此吧
Your highness, Lady Qingqing,
请两位殿下和二小姐
please choose a horse you like.
挑选自己中意的马匹
You choose first, my brother.
王兄先选吧
You two choose first.
你们随便选
I can ride any horse, you know.
反正我什么马都可以驾驭
What about Qingqing?
卿儿呢
Which one do you like?
喜欢哪匹
I'd choose the brown one.
我就要棕色的这匹吧
OK. Then I'll choose the white one.
好 那我就选白马
Have you decided yet?
你们真的选好啦
Don't blame the horse when you lose.
输了不要说马不好
Well, let's see who will be the winner.
好 那我们成败见
Brother,
王兄
the black horse seems to have a bad temper.
这匹黑马看起来性情不太稳
How about we change our horses?
要不你与我换一匹
Sure.
没问题的
I can win with any horse.
我什么马都能赢
Today I compete with you,
今日我与王兄比赛
we're using the number of prey as a standard within two hours.
一个时辰内以猎物的数量为准
Who that has more prey wins.
多者获胜
What do you think?
王兄认为如何
OK.
行啊
Alright.
好
Then I'll do my best
那铭炀便放开手脚
to compete with you.
与王兄一决高下
Don't cry if you lose.
输了别哭
Nangong's horse
南宫的马
doesn't seem right.
看似有些不对劲
Your archery is always excellent.
王兄的箭术一向高超
Why can't you perform well today?
为何今日一反常态
Are you araid of losing
王兄这是怕输
or just let me win deliberately?
还是故意让着铭炀
I never thought of it that way.
我从来都没有这样的想法
Why do you stimulate me?
你又何必激我
In that case,
既如此
you'd better try your best.
那便请王兄全力以赴吧
I want to have a fair fight with you.
我想和王兄堂堂正正地比一场
Nangong,
南宫
why is your horse so disobedient?
你的马怎么这么不听话
That's okay.
无妨
The good horse is hard to tame.
这好马就是难驯服
Well, if it's a good horse,
那既然是好马
give me a try.
也给我试试呗
You?
你
What?
怎么
You can tame it,
就你能驯服得了
can't I?
我就驯服不了了吗
Now is the right time to ask her.
现在正是机会问清楚
OK. Give you.
行 给
Qingqing,
卿卿
why did you avoid me
那天你看完信之后
after reading the letter the other day?
干吗还躲着我
Don't you believe me?
你是不是不相信我
Which letter?
什么信啊
The letter I asked Xiaowu to send to you.
就我让小武给你送的信啊
Didn't you see it?
你没看到吗
Xiaowu?
小武
Letter?
信
Qingqing,
卿卿
you've been avoiding me
自从你知道我有寒毒一事
ever since you found out I had the poison.
经常躲着我
I know you're worried about me.
我知道你是担心我
But now I've found a way
但是如今我已经找到办法
to control the poison.
控制住寒毒了
You really don't have to be burdened.
你真的没必要有负担
Have you cured your glacial poison?
你治好了寒毒
I...
我
You're lying.
你骗人
There's no way to cure it.
根本就没有办法能治好
I looked it up.
我都查过了
Qingqing, listen to me.
卿卿 你听我解释
Let me go.
你放开我
Listen to...
你听我
You shouldn't force other people, brother.
王兄何必强人所难
Don't force Qingqing.
不要逼卿儿
I need to explain it to Qingqing.
我得跟卿卿解释清楚
Many things don't need explanations.
很多事情无须解释
We believe in what our eyes see.
我们相信眼睛看到的
You are in poor health.
王兄身体本来就欠佳
A few days ago, you fainted
前几日又因使用灵力
because of the use of magic power.
消耗精力而晕倒
I was worried about your health
原本来狩猎
when we decided to go hunting.
我就非常担心王兄的身体
If you insist on what you do
倘若王兄执意如此
and neglect your health,
无所顾忌
then I can only
那我只能
send you home and have a rest forcibly.
强行送王兄回府休息了
What happened between us
我俩之间的事
is none of your business.
跟你没有关系
Could you just let us work it out by ourselves?
能不能让我俩自己解决啊
It's almost time to finish the competition.
距离比赛结束的时间就要到了
Your prey is far less than me.
王兄的猎物远不如我
Are you going to throw in the towel?
这是要认输了吗
Can you two just stop arguing?
你们两个别吵了行不行
Qingqing, believe me.
卿卿 你相信我
I hope you can respect Qingqing's choice.
还望王兄尊重卿儿的选择
She doesn't want to see you now.
卿儿现在不想见你
Mingyang,
铭炀
you know that my glacial poison has been sealed.
你明明知道我寒毒已经止住了
Brother,
王兄
you can hide for a while that
你没有灵力的事情
you don't have magic power,
瞒得住一时
but you can't keep the secret forever!
瞒得了卿卿一世吗
If she knows it later,
若日后她知道了
she will be sadder and more guilty
只会比现在更加难过
than he is now.
更加愧疚
Can you bear to see her suffer like this?
你难道忍心看她受此折磨吗
It’s better to have short pains than long ones.
长痛不如短痛
You are never meant to be together.
你们注定有缘无分
What happened?
怎么回事
Stop!
停下
- Qingqing! - Stop!
卿卿 停下
Lady Qingqing!
二小姐
Qingqing!
卿卿
Nangong,
南宫
Don't come over. It's a trap!
别过来 有陷阱
Don't get closer!
别过来
Nangong!
南宫
Your Highness!
殿下
Lord Jin and Lady Qingqing fell into a trap in the woods.
晋王和二小姐掉入林中陷阱
Trap?
陷阱
Brother.
王兄
Nangong,
南宫
are you alright?
没事吧
I'm okay.
我没事
I was tied by the magic-restrained net
这缚灵网捆着我
so I couldn't use my magic power.
一点灵力用不出来
How dare the rob!
好大的胆子
Who the hell
到底是谁
made traps on my hunting grounds!
竟敢在我的猎场动手脚
I always think there's something wrong with this horse.
我总觉得这匹马有问题
That's the case.
果真如此
This thing is so strange.
此事委实奇怪
Few people know
今日来狩猎的事情
about hunting today.
并没有几个人知道
I will get to the bottom of this
此事我定会查个水落石出
and give you a result.
给王兄一个交代
Mingyang,
铭炀
I'm just an idle Lord,
我就是一个闲散王爷
so it's not a big deal if I'm killed.
谋害我也就算了
But if you are the person who is assassinated someday,
如果有一天此人目标是你
then the whole Qiyuan continent will be in chaos.
整个启元大陆会大乱
It's getting late.
天色不早了
What about
不如
I ask someone to send you home to rest?
我派人送王兄回去休息吧
i'll send Qingqing back home.
我送卿儿回去即可
What's wrong?
你怎么了
Did you get hurt?
不会受伤了吧
I seem to have got some internal injuries.
好像是受了点内伤
Your Highness,
太子殿下
it'd be better that
还是我跟你一起
we send Lord Jin back home together.
送晋王回去吧
Fine.
也好
Your Highness,
启禀太子
we found some marks at the scene.
现场发现了一些痕迹
Any evidence?
有证据
Mingyang,
铭炀
the assassination in hunting ground
猎场刺杀这件事情
is a matter of concern.
事关重大
I think you should stay
我认为你应该留下来
and find out who's behind this.
找出幕后的黑手
If the first scene is destroyed,
如果第一现场就这么被破坏掉
the evidence will be lost
那证据流失
and the matter will be bound to fizzle out.
这件事势必就是不了了之
There is no time to lose,
事不宜迟
so you should take charge of it.
这件事就拜托你了
Your Highness, you can go ahead.
太子 你去吧
I'll send Lord Jin back to his home.
我送晋王回府就可以了
Qingqing will send me back, so don't worry about me.
有卿卿送我 你放心
Then be careful on your way.
那你们路上小心
Let's go.
走吧
Be careful.
慢点
Whoever set this up had bad intentions.
此事设计之人用心险恶
We must make it clear.
一定要查清楚
Go. Let's have a check.
走 去看看
Yes.
是
It hurts!
疼啊
It hurts... It hurts...
疼死我了 疼死我了
Put me on the bed.
放我去床上
Lady Qingqing,
路小姐
what happened to Lord Jin?
我家王爷这是怎么了
He suffered an internal injury at the hunting ground.
他在猎场受了内伤
Lady Qingqing,
路小姐
I'm gonna go and find a casual suit for him.
我先去给我们家王爷找件便服
Please wait here for a moment.
您在这儿稍等一会儿
Just go.
你去吧
Qingqing,
卿卿
I can swear to you,
我发誓
the glacial poison in my body has been cleared!
我体内的寒毒真的已经解了
Don't lie to me.
你别骗我啊
I won't cheat you!
我不骗你
I didn't feel any pain when you touched me just now.
你刚碰我 我都没痛吧
Doctor Wu is a highly skilled doctor in No Magic Valley.
吾大夫乃是废灵谷的神医
He had just acquired
他那儿不久前
a panacea
刚得到一味妙方
and then cured my poison.
之后就帮我解了寒毒
Qingqing,
卿卿
all of these are not important.
这些都不重要
What counts is that
重要的是你和我
we can be together forever,
终于可以开心地在一起了
right?
对吧
My lady.
小姐
As you were.
免礼 免礼
You guys go and get some rest.
你们快去休息吧
You scared me, Baihe!
你吓我一跳 百合
My lady,
小姐
I see you are blushing.
我看您这面带桃花
Did anything good happen after you came back?
从猎场回来有何喜事
No.
没
Nothing.
没什么呀
My lady,
小姐
why are you laughing?
您到底在偷笑什么
Nangong's disease has been cured,
南宫的病治好了
so we can get together again!
我们可以在一起了
Is that true, my lady?
真的吗 小姐
You can be with Lord Jin!
您终于可以和晋王在一起了
I'm so happy for you!
百合真为您开心
Your Highness,
王爷
it's time to drink medicinal herbs.
吃药了
This is made with a prescription from Doctor Wu,
这是吾大夫开的方子熬的药
so you have to keep drinking!
您得坚持吃啊
Doctor Wu
这个病呢
can only cure half of my disease.
吾大夫他就只能治一半
The other half...
至于另外一半
I know. It should relys on Lady Qingqing.
我知道要靠卿卿小姐
Your Highness,
王爷
you have lost your magic power.
您这没有了灵力
Could please care more about your safety?
能不能多注意点自己的安全
Thanks to Lady Qingqing
今天幸好是路小姐
who found the problem
早早发现了问题
and changed her horse with you.
同您换了马
Otherwise the result would be unimaginable.
不然后果简直不堪设想
Now I've lost my magic power
我现在呢灵力也没了
and can't protect her.
也没办法保护她
I was a
本来呢
little worried about it.
我心里还是有些担忧的
But now she has great magic power.
但是她现在灵力这么高
She has the ability to protect herself.
还有自保的能力
I can put my mind at ease.
我就放心了
She can not only protect herself.
她不光是能自保
With her magic power now,
卿卿小姐现在的实力啊
she can even protect you.
都可以保护您了
Even though I have no magic power,
我南宫一昕就算没有了灵力
I'm still uninhibited Lord Jin of Qiyuan.
也是潇洒不羁的启元晋王
Today was just an accident.
今天只是个意外
This was not an accident.
这绝不是个意外
Even Xiaowu could also see that
连小武都能看得出来
this had been prepared
此事有备而来
and planned for a long time.
蓄谋已久
You're right.
你说得太对了
It means I've been known
说明我封印灵力这件事情
to seal my magic power.
已经被人知道了
Xiaowu, tell me.
小武 我问你
Did you send the letter to Qingqing
我让你送给卿卿的那封信
by yourself?
你有没有亲手交给她
I couldn't see Lady Qingqing at all.
路小姐根本就见不到
The Lu Mansion was heavily guarded,
路府门禁森严
so I couldn't enter in it.
我根本就进不去
I asked Fu to send the letter.
我便托给阿福代为转交了
The letter that should have been sent to Qingqing
可能转交给卿卿的那封信
had been stopped halfway.
被拦下来了
Haven't she received it?
她没收到
I told him over and over that
我再三叮嘱他
he must deliver it to Baihe by himself.
一定要亲手交给百合
He also promised me.
他也跟我保证了
It could be him.
一定是他
Lu Hongzhu.
路鸿竹
At that time, Lady Qingqing changed her horse with Lord Jin.
当时二小姐与晋王殿下换了马
Crown Prince and Lord Jin also rushed over,
太子殿下和晋王也都赶了过来
so my task failed.
属下行动失败
Please punish me, Your Grace.
还请大人责罚
Qi Yi,
齐翼
you are the servant I value most.
你是我最看重的手下
I'm grateful for your cultivation.
属下一直感恩路大人的栽培
Great.
很好
Crown and Lord Jin
这件事
will definitely investigate this issue thoroughly.
太子和晋王一定会彻查到底
What should you do if you're investigated?
如果查到你头上该怎么做
I see.
属下明白
I did all of these all by myself.
此事皆是属下一人所为
I will find another chance to implement the plan.
属下一定会找时机另行计划
Nangong Yixin is full of tricks.
南宫一昕诡计多端
Don't underestimate his power.
切不可轻敌
Yes.
是
I got you what you asked for.
你要的东西我给你拿来了
I can always trust you.
司空就是司空啊
Just in time.
就是及时
What are you looking at? Help me arrange it.
愣着干吗呀 帮我插一下
OK. OK.
行 行 行
You really have an idle mind
你啊是真有闲心
and still arrange the flowers here.
还在这儿插花
I'm so worried about
猎场的事啊
what happened at hunting ground.
我知道以后担心死了
You are at your leisure!
你倒是清闲
Think about it.
你自己想想
Why did Crown Prince
太子为了赢
kill you to win the game?
为什么下此狠手啊
Not Crown Prince.
不是太子
It was Lu Hongzhu.
是路鸿竹啊
Lu Hongzhu?
路鸿竹
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的
I wrote an anonymous letter to General Murong
我写了一封匿名信给慕容将军
and told him General Han's death was suspicious.
告诉他韩将军之死有蹊跷
He then revealed the thing
慕容将军随后便向铭炀
to Mingyang.
揭发这件事情
And later, the case happened at hunting ground.
再然后猎场就出事了
What does it mean?
这说明什么
It means that Lu Hongzhu
说明路鸿竹
had already known the witness is in my house.
已经知道那名人证在我府上
He can't stay anymore.
他坐不住了
Do you have any evidence?
那你有证据吗
Crown Prince
证据嘛
is searching for evidence.
太子会去找
It's not convenient for me to stand out.
我就不便出头了
Nnagong,
南宫
why do you believe Crown Prince so much?
你干吗总是这么相信太子啊
And also, even if he finds out evidence,
再说了就算太子有证据了
he is so close to Lu Hongzhu,
他跟路鸿竹的关系
will he be fair?
他能秉公处理吗
Mingyang has a good personality.
铭炀他秉性不坏
I believe he will carry out a reasonable judgment.
我相信他能秉公处理
So, what's your next step
不过你这么做
since you decided to do this?
接下来又是如何打算的
Lu Hongzhu
路鸿竹
has forcibly occupied the court for so many years.
他霸占朝堂这么多年
This is a good chance to soften his blow.
正好借此挫挫他的锐气
But now
但现在
I can't promise the safety of the witness,
我怕是无法确保人证安全
so I want to send him to No Magic Valley secretly.
所以我想秘密把他送去废灵谷
I already sent Xiaowu to do it.
我已经派小武去做了
My lady,
小姐
I heard that
我听人说
the real goal of the case yesterday
昨天刺客真正的谋害对象
was Lord Jin.
是晋王殿下
There are a lot of rumors out there
现在外面谣言纷纷
and said that
都在说
it was planned by Crown Prince.
是太子殿下所为
Nonsense!
胡说
Although they had some arguments,
他们兄弟二人虽有矛盾
Crown Prince could
但太子殿下
never kill his brother.
绝不会做出这等事情
People outside don't know what happened
我看外面那些人就是不明就里
and guess by their imagination.
胡乱猜测
Damn it!
简直该死
I heard that Crown Prince
我听说太子殿下
is also finding the whereabouts of the assassin.
也在寻找刺客的下落
But a lot of people are saying that
但是好多人都在议论
Crown Prince is a thief crying "stop thief".
说是太子殿下贼喊捉贼
It was a deliberate act.
故意做戏罢了
No.
不行
I must help His Majesty find out the truth
我得帮殿下查明真相
and prove his innocence.
还他一个清白
My lady,
小姐
His Majesty treats you so badly.
太子殿下都这么对你了
Why do you still thinking about him
你却还在处处为他着想
and help him silently?
默默为他做事
No matter if he loves me or not,
不管他心中有没有我
I can't see him in danger
我都不能看他遭遇险境
as an onlooker.
而无动于衷